{
    "id": "89bedae54c19486584667ee7401671f1",
    "title": "Commonly Confused Words Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Don’t ………….. in bed all day.",
            "description": "To lie is to be down or become horizontal.",
            "answers": [
                "lie",
                "lay",
                "lain"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "9aebd7a6c3fa404d8738d2927899c446"
        },
        {
            "question": "Susie was supposed to go to the party, but she was ill so Joe went ...................... her.",
            "description": "If Joe went instead of Susie, that means he replaced her. If he went without Susie, that means he went alone. Susie didn't accompany him. ",
            "answers": [
                "instead of",
                "without",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "5e1d48c29dae4fd89eb91c02decb52cd"
        },
        {
            "question": "………….. expensive holidays could be the most interesting.",
            "description": "The least can be used before adjectives in the same way as ‘the most’.",
            "answers": [
                "The least",
                "Least",
                "The lesser"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "85da49e91a3b46249fe9bcc34e776f80"
        },
        {
            "question": "He …………….. to me when he said he loved me.",
            "description": "Lied is the past participle of lie.",
            "answers": [
                "laid",
                "lied",
                "lain"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "64ee8907c19446dd9174b0ae426e7c9f"
        },
        {
            "question": "She didn’t let me …………… what she was writing.",
            "description": "Let is followed by an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "see",
                "to see"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "734cf565f5dc4239b6dcc19a815bf703"
        },
        {
            "question": "After questioning they were …………. home.",
            "description": "Let is not normally used in passive forms.",
            "answers": [
                "allowed to go",
                "let go"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "02c56a4ebdc14709867e619b13f0e2b6"
        },
        {
            "question": "My parents had …………….",
            "description": "When 'life' refers to the whole of a person’s life, it is normally countable and is used with articles.",
            "answers": [
                "hard life",
                "a hard life",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e73aa550c8e6400a983d88e777468909"
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………….. you and your husband.",
            "description": "Very much cannot go between like and its object.",
            "answers": [
                "like very much",
                "very much like",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3a0d4d4deaea42949c80ddb1baf12545"
        },
        {
            "question": "I waited ………………… but he didn’t arrive.",
            "description": "Long is mainly used in questions and negatives. In affirmative clauses, we use for a long time.",
            "answers": [
                "long",
                "for a long time",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3ebb5405643443b3950ad81b99cc2631"
        },
        {
            "question": "…………….. carefully – it is moving.",
            "description": "No preposition is used when there is no object after look.",
            "answers": [
                "Look",
                "Look at",
                "Look in"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "988eba7d3c3f4e4fbb74166b8b3db3ae"
        },
        {
            "question": "Paper is made ………… wood.",
            "description": "When a material is changed into a totally different form to make something, we use make from.",
            "answers": [
                "of",
                "off",
                "with",
                "from"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "dbdcf293f935489080a7013c69ce77f6"
        },
        {
            "question": "You …………… work tomorrow if you don’t want to.",
            "description": "Needn’t and don’t have to mean the same. ",
            "answers": [
                "needn't",
                "don't have to",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "66c57e1cf55a45838c31d26f9a97acf7"
        }
    ]
}